Almost there.
Just an easy little hop.
Kinda.
Hey! You wanted
to come this time.
Just a little...
higher.
Heihei?
How?
Hear anything?
There's gotta be
other people out here.
Other villages...
And one day
someone's gonna answer...
Never change.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Ow!
Heihei!
You sweet, beautiful chicken!
Oh, this is amazing!
What are you waiting for?
Let's go home!
We're back!
♪ Sailing from the horizon ♪
♪ Back to our home
Our island ♪
♪ Coming into our view
Beneath the morning sky ♪
♪ We're back! ♪
♪ From new shores
We've been exploring ♪
♪ Returning
To tell our story ♪
♪ Connected
With both the land and sea ♪
♪ Finally we're back! ♪
♪ To who we're meant to be ♪
♪ Who I'm meant to be ♪
♪ Voyaging the sea! ♪
♪ We're back! ♪
♪ The village
Is lush and thriving ♪
♪ Weaving new kites
For flying ♪
♪ Building new homes
And families ♪
♪ Our people
Just keep expanding! ♪
♪ We're back! ♪
♪ Let's pull the roof
Higher! ♪
I can't wait till I retire.
♪ The ancestors
Would be proud ♪
♪ What was once
Was lost has been found! ♪
♪ Finally we're back! ♪
♪ To who we're meant to be ♪
-♪ Who we're meant to be ♪
Do you have to sing?
♪ Yes, we have to sing! ♪
Hey, kids!
♪ Gather 'round
If you wanna hear about ♪
♪ The greatest wayfinder
Of all time ♪
♪ A living legend ♪
♪ And she's besties
With a demigod! ♪
Like, super besties!
♪ Together
They saved our land ♪
♪ And then, like
Totally set us free! ♪
♪ What's next? We'll see! ♪
♪ How much better
Could it be?! ♪
Unless, Maui
was also friends with me.
-Yeah, right.
-Look!
She's coming!
♪ Welcome our brave Moana! ♪
♪ Ooh, I wonder
What she brought us ♪
♪ The new canoe
Needs inspecting ♪
♪ There's always
Something to fix on board ♪
♪ The village believes in her
That's right! ♪
♪ The village believes ♪
I made it past the reef!
Race the chief to shore?
Oh, Dad.
It's never much of a race.
♪ The life is back ♪
-♪ In the water ♪
-Moana!
♪ Our people
Have come out stronger ♪
♪ The voyaging past we honor ♪
♪ Thanks to our daughter
Whoa! ♪
Hey!
♪ Sailing from the horizon ♪
♪ Can't wait
To reach my island ♪
♪ The home I've been
missing ♪
♪ And the life
I'm meant to lead! ♪
♪ We're back!
Moana, she points us to the ♪
♪ Future of Motunui ♪
♪ Connected
With both the land and sea ♪
♪ Oh, finally ♪
♪ We're back ♪
♪ To who we're meant to be ♪
♪ Of the land and sea ♪
♪ Finally ♪
♪ We're back! ♪
♪ To who we're meant to be! ♪
-♪ Who we're meant to be ♪
New fruit!
You're gonna love it.
I don't love anything.
I'm gonna
eat this chicken!
-New look!
-Yep.
We even got our own Pua!
-Oh.
-His name is Bua!
-Coming through!
-Hey! Watch it!
New canoe.
How did she hold up?
Lay it on me.
I mean, it takes a bit
to rotate the sail, but...
-Got it.
-No, no, no.
-Loto, you don't...
-Move.
Oh!
Yikes.
-Hey!
-Hey.
It's called a hair whip.
Learned it from those guys.
So, how'd it go this time?
You found something!
It was in a clearing!
Which I found with
a little help from...
...Heihei,
but this isn't
from our village.
I don't even know
what it's made of,
but it's proof.
There are other people
out there.
I don't know why
we haven't found them yet,
but, Dad, that island,
I think that's where
they're gonna be.
I just have to figure out
how to find those stars.
Whoa!
Moana!
Little sis!
-Big sis!
-Little sis!
Big sis!
I'm gonna get you!
You were gone forever!
It was three days.
But I missed you every...
-What did you bring me?
-Bring you?
You said
you'd bring me a present.
Huh. Well, let me see.
Whoa.
What's it do?
What's it...
Where are we going?
Whoa.
This is the place
of our ancestors.
Where I learned
our people are voyagers.
Where Gramma showed me
who we are.
Gramma!
She said to grab Maui
by the ear and tell him,
"I am Moana of Motunui.
"You will board my boat
"and restore
the heart of Te Fiti."
Pretty good.
Yeah.
How long did it take?
- Few weeks.
- Weeks?
That's longer than forever.
I know.
But it was important.
And, if I hadn't gone,
I never would've
become a wayfinder.
Like our ancient chiefs.
Like the last
great navigator...
Tautai Vasa.
Before Maui
stole Te Fiti's heart
and we stopped voyaging...
Tautai Vasa wanted
to connect our island
to all the people
of the entire ocean.
Because together,
what we can do.
how far we all can go,
it's endless.
And now
that I'm a wayfinder,
it's my job to continue
what he started.
And this...
This is my first clue how.
You should make Maui go,
so you can stay with me!
Well, Maui is out demigodding,
but if he ever shows up,
you grab him by the ear
and tell him that.
Chee Hoo!
Yoo-hoo!
I'm not here to cause trouble.
Just a super chiseled demigod
passing through.
Now, open the portal
to the island,
and I'll be on my way.
And why would I risk
breaking the rules for you
when you've already caused
my boss so much trouble?
Hey, Nalo started it.
And you'll finish it?
Team up with your
precious human again?
Team?
You mean the girl
with the canoe
and that goofy little chicken?
We weren't a team.
I just used her
to get my hook.
Ow. Ow!
Nalo is a god, Maui.
If you try to reconnect
the people of the ocean,
he will destroy you.
And then
he'll destroy her too.
This is between him and me.
Moana has nothing
to do with it.
Oh! You made her
a wayfinder, Maui.
So, now, she has everything
to do with it.
Mystery island? Cool.
I'd like a sample of that.
♪ Moana's gonna find people ♪
Well, eat up.
We don't want
the pork getting cold.
Ooh.
Gotta stop doing that.
Moana...
Tonight isn't just a feast.
Long ago,
there was a title given
to the last great wayfinder
with dreams as big as yours.
A sacred title,
more than a chief,
a Tautai.
Leader, connector
of the entire sea.
My dear,
would you honor us tonight
by accepting this title?
Our people's first Tautai
in a thousand years.
And show us all
just how far we'll go.
Tonight, we drink
from our ancestors' bowl,
as Tautai Vasa once did,
to bestow this title on you.
To connect to our past,
our present,
and the future
that lies beyond.
May the ancestors
continue to guide us.
-Big sis!
-Shh.
I am honored
to serve our people.
May the ancestors
continue to guide us.
Tautai Vasa.
Motufetu should be
under the stars.
What?
Bind the sail!
Lift the oar!
No!
Where are my people?
Tautai Moana.
This is your future
if you cannot find others.
In isolation,
this is how your story ends.
I don't understand.
Returning Te Fiti's heart
was the beginning.
You must brave the storm.
Reconnect our people.
Find Motufetu.
But I don't know
how to reach it.
A fire in the sky
will guide you.
Wait. I don't even know
how far it is.
Farther than I was able to go.
Find Motufetu.
Reconnect us all!
No!
Moana!
Motufetu.
The island
I have to find is Motufetu.
Okay...
Took some searching, but...
Motufetu.
What is it?
An ancient island
where the channels
of the ocean
once came together,
connecting the people
of the entire sea.
Until it was lost. Cursed.
Cursed?
In a terrible storm
of a power-hungry god, Nalo,
who believed he'd be stronger
by separating
the people of the ocean,
to weaken us,
to end our story.
Our ancestors believed
reaching Motufetu
would break Nalo's curse,
restore the channels.
It's the only way to bring
our people together again.
Or our story ends.
We need to convene
a council of...
Chief!
A fire in the sky.
He wants me to follow it.
To new stars.
It could take a lifetime.
Tautai Vasa
didn't make it back at all.
It's a call
from the ancestors, Tui.
But if we never
see her again...
What do you mean,
never see you again?
Simea,
no, I mean, that's...
I don't want you to leave!
Simea...
Mom, this...
It's so fast.
What if...
You're a Tautai now, Moana.
For some things,
we never feel ready.
♪ I know these stars
Above the ocean ♪
♪ Now new skies
Call me by name ♪
♪ And suddenly
Nothing feels the same ♪
♪ I know the path
That must be chosen ♪
♪ But this is bigger
Than before ♪
♪ Winds have changed
Tides turn me ♪
♪ Far away from shore ♪
♪ What waits for me ♪
♪ Forever far from home ♪
♪ From everything ♪
♪ And everyone
I've ever known ♪
♪ What lies beyond? ♪
♪ Under skies
I've never seen ♪
♪ Will I lose myself between ♪
♪ My home and what's unknown ♪
♪ If I go beyond ♪
♪ Leaving all I love behind ♪
♪ With the future
Of our people still to find ♪
♪ Can I go beyond? ♪
♪ There is destiny in motion ♪
♪ And it's only just begun ♪
♪ Now will this life
I've worked so hard for ♪
♪ Come undone? ♪
♪ They're calling me ♪
♪ I must reply ♪
♪ But if I leave ♪
♪ How could
I ever say goodbye? ♪
♪ What lies beyond? ♪
♪ On the vast uncharted sea ♪
♪ Will I lose myself between ♪
♪ All that we know
Right here ♪
♪ And what's out there
Beyond ♪
♪ Leaving all I love behind ♪
♪ With the future
Of our people still to find ♪
♪ Can I go beyond? ♪
♪ If I'm not here
To hold her hand ♪
♪ Will she grow
To understand? ♪
Gramma!
♪ I'll always
Be right beside you ♪
♪ But perhaps
You're meant for more ♪
Oh, what are you
so worried about?
It's not like last time.
Last time,
you weren't old enough
to understand
all you could lose.
Or learn.
But here we are.
Together still.
Just a little different.
I can't see
where your story leads,
but we never stop
choosing who we are.
This is bigger than Motunui.
Bigger than us.
So I will sail to this new sky
to reconnect the people
of the entire ocean.
And then, I will return home.
♪ I'll go beyond ♪
♪ And although
I don't know when ♪
♪ I will reach
These sands again ♪
♪ 'Cause I know who I am ♪
♪ I am Moana! ♪
♪ Of the land and of the sea ♪
♪ And I promise
That is who I'll always be ♪
♪ I must go
I will go ♪
♪ Then we'll know ♪
♪ What lies beyond! ♪
Moana, you need a crew.
Heihei and Pua don't count.
It's the other side
of the ocean.
How could I ask them to...
Our people will rise,
if you let them.
Last time,
the chicken made it.
Well, then I'm gonna
need a bigger canoe.
Oh, yes! Brand-new...
sleek, double-hulled design.
My best canoe yet. Sweet!
Top-of-the-line upgrades
for the crew.
Loto!
I'd like you on the crew.
Oh! Well, we should
do better than this.
A farmer? On the sea?
We're gonna need
to eat more than fish.
You'd need irrigation.
Plant propagation.
Take even my best apprentice,
you'd starve!
Exactly. We need a master.
Yes, you do need... You...
Thanks, Kele! You're the best!
Walked into that one.
Hey, Maui.
It's been a while.
Um, I don't know
where you are, but...
Oh, I could
really use your help.
Maui!
-Oh. Moni.
-It's both of us, actually.
Maui and me.
It's part of a series.
Wow.
You know,
it's too bad Maui isn't here.
You really need someone
who knows all the old stories,
and someone who's,
like, super strong,
and has great hair and just...
I think I know someone else
kinda like that.
Yes!
I'm going with Moana
on a call from the ancestors!
Whoo!
Get ready for some
eyewitness accounts, people!
I'm coming with you.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
I promise.
What if you don't come back?
The ocean
is my friend.
Our friend.
It connects us.
So, there is nowhere
I could ever go
that I won't be with you.
So, you can take
a piece from home.
We love you, Moana!
You might wanna hold on.
Okay, okay, okay.
One more time.
This is not
the end of our story.
This is not where
our destiny is denied.
Together, we rise as one!
Together, we take our freedom!
That guy gets it.
Yep. I mean you, handsome.
Now, all you gotta do
is get my hook.
Get my hook.
Yes! Yes! Come on. You got it.
That's what
I'm talkin' about! Yes!
You're doing it!
Higher. That's it.
Higher! We're almost there.
Just a little...
No, no. No.
What are you...
Don't worry. Come on.
You know me.
I'll get us outta here.
No, I don't need her
to save me.
Again.
'Cause she'll die.
Nalo hates humans even more
than he hates me.
And let me tell you something.
He hates me a lot!
So, the farther Curly
is from any of this,
the better.
We're on our own!
Yeah, I got it.
I would let you out, but...
Well, I'm really hoping
to meet your little friend.
I have plans for you both.
What? Hey...
Enjoy your lunch!
Loto! What are you doing?
I'm making improvements.
Okay.
The canoe is perfect as it is.
Perfection's a myth.
There is only failing,
then learning, then death.
Moni! The oar?
Oh. Of course.
That's why
you're the wayfinder.
No. No, no!
Guys, the entire ocean
is kind of counting on us.
So we've got to rise
to the moment,
stay on course,
and keep everyone
on the canoe.
Wait. Where's the farmer?
Ow!
When will the canoe
stop moving?
Well, we're kind of
on the ocean.
-Moni!
-Loto. Moni's the other one.
Guys, we'll never make it...
...if you don't
embrace the ocean!
You can't
embrace a liquid.
Also, I cannot swim!
You know it feels like
you could...
Okay. That's...
Now everyone looks sad.
And whoever designed
the canoe forgot a bathroom!
Yeah. I did the design,
but we're all here.
Why did
I say yes to this?
I shouldn't even...
I am unclear
as to what you are doing.
Guys!
We wanna reach Motufetu,
break Nalo's curse,
we've gotta come together.
Find. Our. Rhythm!
I don't do sing-alongs!
We'll see about that!
♪ Get up
And get on your feet ♪
♪ It's time
To live your own story ♪
♪ Even if you disagree ♪
♪ Trying is mandatory ♪
♪ Look around ♪
♪ What could
Be better than this?!
Everything's better than this.
Ocean, if you'd be so kind.
♪ C'mon
You just need some sun ♪
♪ Ya can't stay
In there forever ♪
♪ You're gonna
Miss all the fun ♪
♪ Don't you know
T'gether's better ♪
♪ Can't you see? ♪
♪ Nothing is better
Than this!!
I'm gonna be sick.
Well, I know how to help that!
♪ Feel the wind ♪
- ♪ As we're riding the waves!
-  ♪ -Whoo!
♪ The odds are we'll end up
In watery graves
-Loto!
-Observation.
♪ Yeah
We're ebbin' and flowin' ♪
♪ There's no sign of slowin' ♪
♪ We know where we're goin' ♪
♪ So what could be better
Than this? ♪
♪ What could be better
Than this?! ♪
♪ (Better than this) ♪
♪ What could be better than ♪
♪ This? ♪
♪ Woah! ♪
♪ We're starting
To hit a stride ♪
♪ I'm in for a crazy ride ♪
♪ We'll be there in no time ♪
♪ Because
We're in this together ♪
♪ Woahhh ♪
♪ Nothing is better
Than this!
I think I'm going
insane on the sea.
This is so great!
Just give me one grain
of sand and a tree.
♪ Yeah
We're so in the moment ♪
♪ We're rockin' and rollin' ♪
♪ We're friends
With the ocean ♪
♪ So nothing is better
Than this ♪
-Wrong.
-What?
♪ Well...
Lemme give you a correction ♪
♪ Even though
The song is clever ♪
♪ The answer
To your question ♪
♪ "What could
Possibly be better?" ♪
♪ Technic'lly speaking
Perfection's a myth ♪
♪ Even though
The journey's epic ♪
♪ Something better
Could exist ♪
♪ But that's why I'm always
Designing, aligning ♪
♪ Combining ideas
And always refining! ♪
♪ I'm a real bright thinker
And a genius when I tinker ♪
♪ With a love
Of problem solving ♪
♪ As a model canoe sinker ♪
♪ We're failing fantastic'lly
Yes, we're a mess ♪
♪ And we're messing up
Drastic'lly ♪
♪ Falling on your face
Is the best! ♪
♪ If you do it wrong
Then you run another test! ♪
♪ Yes!
It's really simple actu'lly ♪
♪ The motto of Loto
'Till her very last breath ♪
♪ There's really only failing
Then learning, then death!
Whoa!
♪ What could be better
Than this? ♪
♪ Literally nothing
Better than this! ♪
♪ What could be better
Than this? ♪
♪ Really truly
Nothing better than this! ♪
Come on, Kele.
The ocean's our friend.
♪ We're starting
To understand! ♪
Just take me back to land!
♪ We'll get to that island ♪
♪ Even if it's taking
Forever ♪
♪ Woahhh! ♪
♪ Nothing is better
Than this! ♪
Everybody now!
-♪ Feel the air ♪
-♪ In our hair ♪
-♪ Watch us soar ♪
-♪ Man the oar ♪
-♪ Going where ♪
-♪ No one's gone before! ♪
♪ Woah! ♪
♪ What could be better
Than this?! ♪
You've got it, Kele!
♪ Woah... ♪
♪ What could be better than ♪
♪ This!!!!! ♪
Um...
Isn't that what
we were supposed to follow?
Uh... Let's...
Nobody panic. I'm sure...
this happened for a reason.
Yeah, it's probably
a good thing, right?
Hey!
Moni! Grab the oar!
I'm trying.
Something's wrong
with the canoe!
It is not the canoe.
It's the current!
What?
Hey, ocean.
So, I kinda wasn't given
a lot of directions
other than "follow the comet."
So, if you're telling me
to change course,
a little thumbs-up
would be super awesome.
Land?
Land!
It's Motufetu!
We found it.
Really quickly.
Do I hear people?
That's no island.
And those
aren't people.
-Kakam...
-Mora?
We've gotta go!
This is so embarrassing.
A farmer murdered by coconuts.
Oh. So, they're just
ignoring us?
That's good. Isn't it?
Is it... Is that good?
Okay. You guys?
Cargo hold.
She's using centrifugal force
to increase our velocity.
Moana!
Ha! Bye-bye.
Thanks for the ride!
Bring it on, coco...
Nuts.
Whoa. Whoa, whoa.
Listen to me!
We are on a sacred voyage!
You will release us.
Wait. Wait!
Ow!
Ow, ow, ow!
Whoa. What are you doing?
What is happening?
Uh... That is...
Fanfic.
You dolt. They're asking
if you drew it,
'cause they want you
to translate that picture.
Oh!
Oh.
Oh. Your home island
is in the same sea
as Motufetu.
And when Nalo
divided the ocean
to weaken the people
of the sea,
your ancestors were
disconnected from their home.
But you thought you'd finally
found the way back
when you ran
into this giant clam.
And now, you're worried
you'll stay separated forever.
This whole time,
they've just been trying
to get home.
But if we help you
defeat the clam,
you'll help us reach Motufetu.
Together.
Hello? We're still jelly!
How're we gonna beat that?
Floppy can't even
wiggle a finger.
Well, our muscles
are full of neurotoxin, so...
Wait. Wait. Hang on.
A clam is basically
one giant muscle.
So, we get close enough
with that stuff,
shoot it in the ganglion,
it's goodnight clam,
hello Motufetu.
Do you think that'll work?
Oh. You want us to do it.
It'd be easier
if we're not jelly.
Ooh. Don't worry.
They can fix that.
How?
What is that?
Tastes like coconut.
It just went right over
the top of us, didn't it?
Okay, where do we get
the toxin for the clam?
A dream from both ends.
Come on. We gotta go!
What?
We made a deal.
We take out the clam,
and then you're helping us
get to Motufetu.
You are small but mighty.
Whoa.
I think
it's a warriors' salute,
to show us respect.
Or it's goodbye
in case we croak.
Wow.
How do we shoot
the ganglion
if we don't know
what it looks like?
I think
we're gonna know
what a ganglion looks like
when we see it.
Yeah.
So, I just...
And Motufetu, here we come?
Mission accomplished.
No. No, no, no!
And this is why
you always have a backup.
And a third.
Well, a fourth
would be lunacy.
No!
Chee Hoo!
We gotta get out!
Wait! What are you...
Hey! No...
- Moni! Moni!
- Moana!
Moana!
Moana?
Gotta say,
I enjoyed that.
Kakamora!
You did this!
Made an assumption there.
Fascinating.
It's like an acid.
Can I get a Chee Hoo?
Oh, yeah!
Now,
I just gotta get my baby.
Maui!
- The tattoo moves.
- Hey.
- The tattoo moves!
- Ow. No. No, no, no.
Listen to me.
I am a demigod...
-Lucky!
-Stop it!
I want to be slapped
by the tattoo.
Hey!
Okay. Rule number one...
No.
Just... Okay. Someone...
Guys, could you please
just roll me back?
- I'll roll you back!
- No, no, no.
Not him.
This is what happens
when you meet your heroes.
Oh! I know, right?
Okay.
Rule number one.
You never saw me like this.
Even though
I still look very cool.
You look like a kidney stone.
And you look like someone
who would know what that is.
Now...
Well, hello, Bacon.
Okay. I feel like
there's some backstory
that I need
to get caught up on.
-Oh. Um...
-Actually, you know what?
Scratch that.
I don't wanna
get attached if y'all...
You know what I mean?
Which you guys won't.
You're not gonna do that.
I don't even know
why I said that.
The point is,
there's some serious god stuff
going down...
So, I'mma go
handle my business.
All right. Be back in a bit.
Until then,
stay alive, talk to no one.
And, if you see
a crazy bat lady, run.
She is the worst.
Stay away, or you will die.
Be good. Maui, out!
Boat snack!
Boat snack.
Where's Moana?
Simea?
Simea! Oh!
How are you here?
I'm not.
You got sucked inside
a giant clam
and our story will end
'cause now, you'll never help
the people of the ocean
and your ancestors
will be, like,
"Moana, we hate you forever.
Forever. Forever."
Huh?
I got this.
You got this.
Relax.
I don't bite.
Peka might.
It's been a while
since I've seen a wayfinder.
Love the oar.
Would you like
to see me use it?
Ooh. Feisty.
Well, we have that
in common, Moana.
The human who's
"got all the gods talking"!
Who are you?
Matangi.
Guardian of this
little slice of paradise.
-Oh!
-Hmm.
You live here?
Not by choice.
Maui never mentioned me?
Oh! Probably too busy
playing with his tattoo.
Huh?
Well, come on, then.
Um, I'm not
going anywhere with you.
-I need to...
-Get outta here,
break Nalo's curse,
find Motufetu.
Here to help.
You know the way to Motufetu?
You think you can
only get somewhere
if you know the way?
That's kinda
what wayfinding is.
Ugh!
So much to learn.
A true wayfinder doesn't
know the path at all.
That's the whole point.
To find your way
to what's never been found.
If you wanna
break Nalo's curse,
you gotta stop
playing it safe, sis.
Get a little lost.
Why would I listen
to anything you say?
Because Nalo trapped me, too.
I want you to beat Nalo,
'cause then, I'll be free.
What?
♪ I've been stuck
A thousand years... ♪
♪ Just fading
Wading through the fears... ♪
♪ This giant clam
Gets real old, my dear ♪
♪ So come real close, ♪
♪ I'll let you know ♪
♪ How you can
Get out of here... ♪
There's always another way
to get where you need to go.
You just have to think
a little different.
Different how?
Glad you asked.
♪ Get lost! Cut loose! ♪
♪ And lose your way! ♪
♪ There ain't no fun
In holdin' back, babe ♪
♪ You gotta enjoy the thrill
Of livin' dangerously ♪
♪ You've got a long, long way
To go ♪
♪ Keep playin' safe
You'll never know ♪
♪ The rules
Are ours to break! ♪
♪ Come on, babe! ♪
♪ It's time to get lost ♪
That is terrible advice.
Mmm.
Then you're not listening.
♪ Take a look around ♪
♪ Not right and left
But up and down! ♪
♪ 'Cause on the edge
It's all about ♪
♪ Living bold and free ♪
♪ Expand your mind to see ♪
♪ And put your trust in me
Because ♪
♪ You've got potential ♪
♪ To travel the distance ♪
♪ I've been existential ♪
♪ And lost to existence ♪
♪ And there is no map ♪
♪ To your destination ♪
♪ No explanation
To solve this equation ♪
♪ We gotta get lost!
Cut loose! ♪
♪ And lose our way! ♪
♪ There ain't no fun
In holdin' back, babe ♪
♪ You gotta enjoy the thrill
Of livin' dangerously ♪
♪ You got a long, long way
To go ♪
♪ Keep playin' safe
You'll never know ♪
♪ The rules
Are ours to break! ♪
♪ Whaddya say? Look... ♪
♪ Don't you know
How good you have it? ♪
♪ You're all
That's stopping you ♪
♪ For me
I'm stuck like static ♪
♪ Can you imagine? ♪
♪ A life this tragic
In the gloom! ♪
♪ You've got a chance
So take it ♪
♪ I know you're scared
But life's unfair! ♪
♪ It's full of choices
Big and small ♪
♪ But trust the fall ♪
♪ And you can have it all! ♪
♪ Get lost! Cut loose! ♪
♪ And lose your way! ♪
♪ There ain't no fun
In holdin' back, babe ♪
♪ (You gotta) Enjoy the thrill
Of livin' dangerously ♪
♪ You got a long long way
To go ♪
♪ Keep playin' safe
You'll never know ♪
♪ The rules
Are ours to break! ♪
♪ Get lost! Hah! ♪
♪ Get lost! No! ♪
There's always another way,
Moana.
What are you gonna do?
Get lost.
♪ Woah! Get lost! ♪
There's always another way.
Portal of the gods.
Won't get you all the way
to Motufetu.
But it'll shorten the commute
for you and your crew
and Mr. Coconut Oil.
Who's Mr...
Ugh.
Always has to make
an entrance.
-Maui!
-Do not fear!
You have been rescued! Whoo!
She opened it?
This was your plan,
to keep me in a snot cave
because you want us
to go together?
Well, I certainly did not
keep you for the conversation.
Huh? Wait!
Well, shall we?
You can't leave?
Break Nalo's curse...
and maybe, one day,
we'll see each other again.
Remember, there's always
another way
even if you have to get lost
to find it.
Good luck, Tautai Moana.
You got this.
If Nalo finds out I helped,
we'll die by lightning.
Maui looked good.
Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa!
I'm kissing the pig!
Happy, happy, happy! Hey, hey!
We're in a portal of the gods!
You guys! Together again!
Plus Maui. Wait, wait.
Where's Maui?
'Sup, Curly?
Maui!
Could've told me
we're doin' new outfits.
Been rockin' leaves
on my cheeks
for a thousand years.
I can't believe you're here!
Hey, buddy. I missed ya.
Yeah.
Oh. Sorry.
That was weird.
Was that weird?
This is
the greatest day of my life.
Love this guy.
Not creeping me out at all.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
Pua! This is Pua.
Ooh. And did you meet
the Kakamora?
I thought
he'd do us in on the clam,
but it turns out
he was super great
'cause otherwise, I never
would have met Matangi,
who's great, by the way,
- and found you, and now...
- Curly!
...we're gonna break
Nalo's curse together and...
Sorry. You go.
You're all gonna die.
What?
Nalo didn't just hide
Motufetu in a storm.
He hid it
in a monster storm
in a cursed ocean
you can't escape from
and then sunk it
to the bottom of the sea.
Which means
a human can't reach it.
So, unless
I break the curse,
you just bought a one-way
ticket to deadsville,
which is why I didn't want you
coming out
in the first place
'cause now you're stuck
and you're gonna die,
your crew's gonna die,
and this time,
so is the chicken.
But...
it's great to see you.
And we're here.
Good one, Maui,
but this place
looks perfectly nice.
And look!
The constellation!
It's right there!
Guys...
The ancestors wouldn't have
called if we couldn't do this.
Unless it was a butt dial.
That'll make sense
in 2,000 years.
Tautai Vasa
said reaching Motufetu
is the only way
to give our people a future.
If he knows so much,
how come he didn't
tell you it was...
...sunk?
Because he told me to follow
the fire in the sky.
And that led me
straight to you.
Which makes sense,
'cause if Nalo thinks
he's stronger
by keeping people apart...
Then maybe the way
to break his curse
is by coming together.
You lift the island,
and I step on it.
"Maui and Moana,
together again!
"They're so amazing!"
This is gonna work.
Right, ocean?
Ocean?
Moana...
The ocean
cannot help you here.
Gramma!
Actually, I believe
that's a welcome gift
from Nalo.
Hmm.
Take that, sucka!
Humans, get to your positions,
work together,
and let's do this!
We really gotta talk about
your recruiting process.
Gramps! Down below.
Hate these guys.
Hey! I'm an elder.
And I'm 3,000 years old.
Which makes me elder-er.
Just gotta outrun 'em
till sunrise.
Oh. Are they nocturnal?
Uh, sure. Chee Hoo!
Oh, yeah!
Whoo!
Did he just wink at us?
Behind us!
Hang on!
Moana, we can't turn
that tight with this sail.
It'll work!
Moana!
Moni!
Moana! Moana!
No! The oar!
Moni!
Moni...
We'll figure this out.
- The ancestors...
- Moana...
Tautai Vasa's canoe...
Uh, it's a bad time to say,
"I told you so,"
so I'm not gonna do that
'cause that would
make you feel worse.
-Just...
-But I believe in you.
No one else does.
There you go.
Walk it off, champ. What?
I was being nice.
Ow. Ow!
No purple nurples. Stop. Ow!
Okay, I'll talk to her!
I know, Maui.
It's just...
Every time I think I know
what I'm supposed to do,
everything changes.
I can't...
Moni almost died!
If I'm the reason our people's
story just ends...
This is serious!
Is something distracting you?
Maybe breaking the curse
is like you said,
we gotta work together.
I pull it from the sea,
but a human has to land
on its shores.
Look, I get it.
No one likes
sucking at their job.
Why are you even here?
Because...
I've been low before.
And I couldn't
see a way forward.
And then someone came along.
Someone who I underestimated.
And she lifted me up.
I haven't done anything right
since I left my island.
Hey...
There is a way out.
You wanna get through it?
You just gotta Chee Hoo it.
You are so bad at this.
I'm the best at this.
I was a human, but now,
I'm a demigod.
You never know what's next.
Yeah, I do.
Nalo's monster storm!
Well, you wanna
get through it?
Stop trying...
♪ Here's the thing... ♪
♪ You're down in the dumps ♪
♪ You think you're way off
Your game ♪
♪ But you can turn it around
Come on ♪
♪ Remember your name! ♪
♪ Don't waste
All this energy ♪
♪ 'Cause you got the remedy ♪
♪ And I know your legacy! ♪
♪ You've got
Greatness inside ♪
♪ And you just
Gotta believe ♪
♪ You think
You don't have the tricks ♪
♪ But they're right
Up your sleeve ♪
♪ These waters
Are threatening ♪
♪ But you bring
The reckoning ♪
♪ So drop all the fear
And the questioning ♪
♪ I need a...
Can I get a... ♪
♪ CHEE HOO? ♪
♪ Who are you...
Who are you... ♪
-♪ Who are you ♪
-♪ Gonna be? ♪
♪ You're gonna, you're gonna ♪
-♪ A-make some ♪
-♪ History ♪
♪ Come on-a
Moana ♪
♪ Go get your destiny ♪
♪ Could I get a...
Can I get a... ♪
♪ Can I get a...
CHEE HOO?! ♪
-♪ You gotta ♪
-♪ You wanna ♪
♪ You needa level up ♪
-♪ Go show 'em ♪
♪ Tell 'em enough's enough ♪
♪ Come on-a
Moana ♪
♪ Go get your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a...
Lemme hear a... ♪
♪ Can I get a CHEE HOO?! ♪
♪ Here's the deal... ♪
♪ That bullying storm god
Skips leg day for real ♪
♪ Can you imagine the legend
This epic voyage reveals? ♪
♪ You think
That it's doomsday?! ♪
♪ To me it's just Tuesday ♪
♪ You know
I don't come to play ♪
♪ Come to play ♪
♪ And you're clever ♪
♪ I never give you
Enough credit ♪
♪ And under pressure
You measure up! ♪
♪ You even taught me
A lesson! Heh, ♪
♪ I'm not surprised
You learned from the best! ♪
♪ Takes a whole lot
But count me impressed! ♪
♪ Can't give up now
You got me invested! ♪
♪ Not many humans that
I call a bestie! ♪
♪ CHEE HOO! ♪
♪ Who are you...
Who are you... ♪
♪ Who are you gonna be? ♪
♪ You're gonna, you're gonna ♪
♪ A-make some history ♪
-♪ Come on-a ♪
-♪ Moana ♪
♪ Go get your destiny ♪
♪ Could I get a...
Could I get a... ♪
♪ CHEE HOO?! ♪
♪ It's my turn to give
A motivational speech ♪
♪ It's your job to finally
Practice what you preach ♪
♪ Because of you
I'm a better me ♪
♪ And I didn't even think
That was a possibility! ♪
♪ You got me
Out of mess after mess ♪
♪ Demigod in distress ♪
♪ But now
The roles are reversed ♪
♪ You're being
Put to the test ♪
♪ It's fine
'Cause we gotta plan ♪
♪ For breaking the curse ♪
♪ And even though
Odds couldn't be worse ♪
♪ I'm making a bet
On the bravest and greatest ♪
♪ Of wayfinders
I've ever met!
♪ Who are you...
Who are you... ♪
♪ Who are you gonna be? ♪
♪ You're gonna, you're gonna ♪
♪ A-make some history ♪
♪ Come on-a
Moana ♪
♪ Go get your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a...
'Cause I need a... ♪
♪ Lemme hear a...
CHEE HOO! ♪
♪ You gotta, you wanna ♪
♪ It's time to level up! ♪
♪ Go show 'em, go show 'em ♪
♪ Tell 'em enough's enough! ♪
♪ Come on-a
Moana ♪
♪ Go get your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a...
Lemme hear a... ♪
♪ CHEE HOO! ♪
♪ Moana!
Come on-a ♪
♪ Unlock your destiny ♪
♪ Lemme hear ya
Make 'em fear ya ♪
♪ Can I get a...
CHEE HOO! ♪
♪ Come on-a
Moana ♪
♪ Go find your destiny ♪
♪ Can I get a...
Lemme hear a... ♪
-♪ CHEE HOO! ♪
Go get 'em, princess.
Still not a princess.
Well, a lot of people
think you are.
Uh...
I know what I've asked of you
is a lot...
that our canoe is in
really rough shape,
but I believe that,
together, we...
We found a way to fix it.
With a little help
from the ancestors, yeah.
I did the decorations.
We used the chicken.
Respect.
Nalo wants to end our story.
But we're not
letting that happen.
We just have to outsmart him,
find some new tricks
he's never seen before.
Well, I have been
working on some ideas.
Also, we do have a demigod.
Sure, he's a little scruffy,
but, you know,
better than nothing.
I think you look great.
Okay. We sail to the heart
of Nalo's storm.
Once I raise the island,
you all have to get to it.
It'll be harder than anything
we've faced before.
So, if anyone wants to...
I spent my whole life
learning our people's stories.
Because of you,
I get to live one.
All right, then.
Let's break a curse.
Yeah.
Been a while
since I pulled
an island from the sea.
I know I have to bend
at the knees.
I have great posture.
You know what? You, armpit.
He's growing on me.
Like a wart.
That's beautiful.
Okay, we do this,
we make it home.
Curly.
It's a storm.
Just a really big one.
Well, now I kind of miss
the lava monster.
Um, that's a big wave.
We can go around it.
Everyone,
get to your positions!
Be ready to switch it up.
You, smart-stuff,
you might wanna
check the sundial.
Why? What time is it?
-It's Maui time!
Whoo!
Let's lift an island and show
this windbag who's boss!
Yeah!
Bring the thunder!
I mean,
it's kinda fun, right?
Chee Hoo!
Yeah! Whoo!
Booyah!
Switch it up,
we're going over.
-Loto?
-On it!
Eat it, Nalo!
Yeah, how 'bout this?
Wait, what?
Yeah!
Count it!
Oh, come on!
They keep coming for us!
We gotta turn! Guys?
No, no, no.
Maui!
It's okay. I got half of 'em.
Scoreboard.
Well, Nalo's a cheater.
And a coward for...
avoiding... you know.
He doesn't care about you.
Oh, he cares about me.
I'm saying it's humans
he wants to stop... us.
Why are you smiling?
'Cause we can use it.
Distract Nalo,
let him come after us
while Maui
reaches the center
and lifts the island.
-We switch it up.
-Okay.
Curly, you couldn't
outmaneuver the storm before.
How you gonna do it now?
I think I have figured it out.
I will need to chop the mast.
If you keep coming back
to help us,
we'll never break
Nalo's curse.
We can draw the storm, Maui.
It's the only way.
Go as fast as you can.
Uh, look, I could
pull up a million islands,
but, if you're not there
to land on them, then...
See you out there, Maui.
I'll see ya out there, Moana.
Bacon, Eggs...
Giant hawk!
So serious.
See ya on the island!
Loto!
Move!
The spinny thing is coming!
Probably should have
prototyped this.
Bingo bango!
Loto! You're a genius.
Well, I couldn't have done it
without Moni.
Hold on!
Not a lot of leverage!
He found Motufetu!
Nalo knows he found it.
The curse won't be broken
till we reach the island.
We still have to reach
the island!
Go!
Little busy.
It's another wave.
We need more speed.
We have to drop weight.
Come on, kid!
Hang on!
Turn!
Lift it!
No!
Maui!
Maui...
No!
Moana!
We're lost!
I don't know
what to do!
There's no way out!
I can't...
There's a--
There's no way!
There's another way.
There's always another way.
There's another way
to reach the island!
There's another way!
- No! Moana, you can't!
- It's too far!
- Find Maui!
- Moana!
No! Moana!
Moana?
Moana!
Moana...
Moana.
Moana, you can't.
Please...
Please.
Together still.
Just a little different.
♪ We'll go beyond ♪
♪ And we'll reach it
Side by side ♪
♪ We are rising
With the tide ♪
♪ No shore left unexplored ♪
♪ Racing toward beyond ♪
♪ Where we all begin again ♪
♪ Where our sky and
Our horizon never end ♪
♪ We can rise ♪
♪ We will rise ♪
♪ We will go beyond ♪
Wow!
You leveled up.
Yeah.
Uh... So, does this mean...
Yes. My tattoos are still
cooler than yours.
Happy dance!
That was such
a crazy...
And then... Hang on. Oh, wow!
Yeah.
Moana! You're alive!
Ocean!
I missed you.
Come on. Come on, now.
Little bit more.
Raisin' an island
really works up an appetite.
Oh, you smell so good.
It's Motunui.
Home.
That one's his.
I now speak Kakamora.
There's so much
out there.
Yeah.
And who knows?
Maybe one day, we'll find...
I'm gonna need you
to stop doing that.
People?
It's people!
Boom! Nailed it.
Ugh. This is a mess.
You're welcome.
Hey, how's it going?
Awesome hair whip.
All right. Guys,
I'm looking for a Simea.
Hi.
Is there a Simea here?
Huh?
I'm Simea.
You're her, all right.
Uh, let me just, um...
Maui!
Moanabes!
Hold that a sec!
I thought you'd be bigger.
Yeah. Like, a lot bigger.
Okay. Your sister sent me
with a present for ya.
Straight from Motufetu.
Wow.
What's it do?
Little sis!
Big sis!
I like what you brought me.
We may have
brought a little more.
This is just the beginning.
♪ We set a course to find ♪
♪ A brand new island
Everywhere we roam ♪
♪ We keep our island
In our mind ♪
Boat snack!
♪ And when it's time
To find home ♪
Boat snack upgrade.
♪ We know the way ♪
♪ We are explorers
Reading every sign ♪
♪ We tell the stories
Of our elders ♪
♪ In a never-ending chain ♪
♪ We keep our island
In our mind ♪
♪ And when it's time
To find home ♪
♪ We know the way ♪
Chee Hoo!
♪ I know these stars
Above the ocean ♪
♪ Now new skies
Call me by name ♪
♪ And suddenly
Nothing feels the same ♪
♪ I know the path
That must be chosen ♪
♪ But this is bigger
Than before ♪
♪ Winds have changed
Tides turn me ♪
♪ Far away from shore ♪
♪ What waits for me... ♪
♪ Forever far from home ♪
♪ From everything
And everyone I've ♪
♪ Ever known ♪
♪ What lies beyond? ♪
♪ Under skies
I've never seen ♪
♪ Will I lose myself between ♪
♪ My home and what's unknown ♪
♪ If I go beyond ♪
♪ Leaving all I love behind ♪
♪ With the future
Of our people still to find ♪
♪ Can I go beyond? ♪
♪ There is destiny in motion ♪
♪ And it's only just begun ♪
♪ Now will this life
I've worked so hard for ♪
♪ Come undone ♪
♪ They're calling me ♪
♪ I must reply
But if I leave ♪
♪ How could I ever
Say goodbye? ♪
♪ I'll go beyond ♪
♪ And although
I don't know when ♪
♪ I will reach
These sands again ♪
♪ 'Cause I know who I am ♪
♪ I am Moana! ♪
♪ Of the land and of the sea ♪
♪ And I promise
That is who I'll always be ♪
♪ I must go ♪
♪ I will go ♪
♪ Then we'll know ♪
♪ What lies beyond! ♪
Hmm.
A human should never have
been able to reach Motufetu
or break my curse.
Well...
I, of course,
have no idea how she did it.
Nalo, I paid my debt.
We are finished.
No.
We're just getting started.
Oh. Sorry.
Are we not doing evil laughs?
-Didn't realize.
-Mmm.
Just that
she humiliated me as well.
I completely relate to what
you're feeling right now.
If you ever
wanna talk about...
Ow!
Okay. Too soon.
Do you wanna hear a song?
I've got a new one.
It's called Funky Crab Legs.
♪ Funky crab legs
Funky crab legs ♪
♪ One, two, three, four, five
Six, seven, eight, nine, ten ♪
Something like that.
Good for counting.